Guide to the Jane Lathrop Stanford Papers SC0033B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, 1868-1905; Series 1; 6 Linear Feet
  - Outgoing, 1860-1905
    - Jordan, David Starr
      - 1903 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - LS. regarding planting Japanese cherry trees near his house, 3-Feb-03
        - LS. regarding application of Emile Deschamps, 13-Feb-03
        - LS. wants to send books to the University of Tokio [sic], 19-Feb-03
        - LS. surprised that space is filling up; likes Dr. Branner's spirit; fears "stone age" will not be over for sometime, 19-Feb-03
        - LS. outside company not to have control of any campus building; intends to arrange for hospital off campus, 18-Apr-03
        - LS. regarding four patients in Encina Hall, 18-Apr-03
        - ALS. wants copy of report on salaries, 29-Apr-03
        - ALS. transmitting invitation to students for a garden fete on Leland Jr.'s birthday, 30-Apr-03
        - LS. going to send statement of entire amount of money spent on University, May 20, 1903
        - ALS. wants to read his proposed article on Ross affair, June 11, 1903
        - LS. concerning gift of his library, June 12, 1903
        - TLS. will continue hygiene dept. for two years, June 12, 1903
        - TLS. no student help to be employed, June 12, 1903
        - TLS. won't pay for items not ordered through business office, June 12, 1903
        - LS. will not consent to publication of his article on Ross affair, June 13, 1903
        - LS. enjoying stay in Ceylon; next month in India, 30-Oct-03
        - PC from Darjeeling, 21-Nov-03
        - PC from Port Said, 28-Dec-03
      - 1904 Jan-Sep (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - TLS. not buying art at present, 7-Jan-04
        - TLS. congratulations on birth of son, 7-Jan-04
        - ALS. thoughts on Stillman tragedy; glad to hear Eric is doing well; her itinerary, Jan 21, 1904
        - LS. please with information about Dr. R. J. Campbell, July 25, 1904
        - LS. regrets calling of Prof. James without consultation; turned over all responsibility of the Educational Dept. to Board of Trustees [original and typed copy], 9-Aug-04
        - ALS. introducing Mrs. F. W. Richardson, 14-Aug-04
        - ALS. regarding correspondence of Mr. Horace Davis which she did not see [original and 1 mss copy], 22-Aug-04
        - LS. deplores publicity in building operations; dislikes reference to "stone age", 10-Sep-04
        - L. enclosure sent to her by mistake, 23-Sep-04
      - 1904 Oct-1905 Feb (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - L. invitation for eight University professors for Tuesday luncheon, 1-Oct-04
        - ALS. wants three more at dinner party, 3-Oct-04
        - LS. welcome news of football victory; visited Harvard and Yale; anecdote re ancestor John Lathrop; visit with Lathrop relatives in Norwich, CT, 4-Dec-04
        - LS. memorial services may be held in church provided minister speaks; not to be used for secular services, 28-Dec-04
        - LS. uneasy regarding conduct of Roble; troubled about girls in sororities, Dec 1904?
        - LS. thanks for sending his books, 3-Jan-05
        - ALS. in San Jose on doctor's advice; does not feel well enough to resume old duties, 5-Feb-05
  - Lathrop, Charles, 1893-1902
    Lathrop, Charles G., (Charles Gardner), 1849-1914
    - Outgoing Correspondence as J. L. Stanford's business manager, 1901-1902 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Tel to Thos. H. Hubbard re sale, 1901 Aug 6
      - Tel to Thos. H. Hubbard re choice of bank for P.I. Co. money, 1901 Aug 9
      - TL to Thos. H. Hubbard re directors of P. I. Co., 1901 Dec 2
      - TL to Geo. E. Crothers re receipt for Mrs. Stanford, 1901 Dec 10
      - TL to Thos. H. Hubbard re compensation for Horace G. Platt, attorney for P. I. Co., 1901 Dec 12
      - TL to Thos. H. Hubbard re. Crocker Estate Co., 1901 Dec 16
      - TL. to Hon. E. F. Loud re communication on postmaster at Stanford, 1902 Jan 2
      - TL to T. H. Hubbard re letters he has forwarded to Mrs. Stanford, 1902 Jan 14
      - TL to Geo. H. Waggoner re property in Albany, NY, 1902 Jan 14
      - to Edwin Hawley re Mexican Int. Railroad Bonds [letter damaged], 1902 Jan 21
      - TL to Speyer and Co. re bonds, 1902 Feb 6
      - TL to John Matzki re water supply problem, 1902 Mar 6
      - TL to Chas. E. Hodges re taking care of art work being shipped, 1902 May 5
      - TL to Chas. E. Hodges re instructions on unpacking art work, 1902 May 7
      - TL to H. R. McCullough re RR pass for Mrs. Stanford, 1902 May 31
      - TL to Robert Ritchie re RR pass for Mrs. Stanford, 1902 May 31
      - TL to George Goddard re purchasing the "Goddard Collection," with Goddard's letter to Lathrop about its content, 1902 June 12
      - TL to F. W. Covey re advertising horses for sale, 1902 July 31
      - Tel to J. C. Stubbs re moving Mrs. Stanford's RR car, 1902 Oct 6
      - TL to George Goodman re bid for walkways in Memorial Court, 1902 Oct 6
      - TL to J. D. McGilvrary re bid for stone pedestals in Memorial Court, 1902 Oct 6
      - TL to James Rennie re grape harvest at Vina, 1902 Oct 9
      - L to George Adderson re reserving Assembly Hall for lecture by Dr. Chas. H. Brown, 1902 Oct 22
      - TL to S. F. Leib re receipt of Power of Attorney, 1902 Nov 12
    - Incoming Correspondence as J. L. Stanford's business manager, 1893-1902 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Arranged alphabetically by correspondent; includes in addition to other miscellaneous correspondence, letters from the following:
      - Camerino, Achille. ALS. re marble shipment, 1901 Feb 25
      - Camerino, Achille. ALS. re shipping marble with bill for packing, 1901 Mar 28
      - Douty, F. S. TEL enclosing statement of bills payable, 1900 Apr 4
      - Dart, Walter C. ALS. re. sending his report on Vina., 1898 June 9
      - Harriman, E. H. Tel. re hauling Mrs. Stanford's RR car east, 1902 Oct 6
      - Hubbard, T. H. Tel. re sale of Mexican RR bonds, 1901 Aug 6
      - Hubbard, T. H. TL (copy). re transferring various RR stocks in settlement of obligations to P.I. Co., 1898 Sep 6
      - Hubbard, T.H. TL (copy). re. factions in the Pacific Improvement Co., 1901 Dec 10
      - Hubbard, T.H. TL (copy). re. factions in the Pacific Improvement Co., 1901 Dec 23
      - Hubbard, T.H. TL (copy). re. property at Pacific Grove., 1902 Jan 9
      - McCarthy, John B. Tel. congratulations on government suit, 1896 Mar 2
      - Pellet, H.A. ALS. re his salary for work at Vina; includes letter from Leland Stanford to Pellet, Jan. 11, 1893, setting his salary at $1000, 1893 July 23
      - Rennie, James. TL re grape harvest at Vina, 1902 Oct 8
      - Ritchie, R. R. TL re RR pass for Mrs. Stanford, 1902 May 29
      - Steinman, B. U. TEL re congratulations on government suit, 1896 Mar 3
      - Tubbs, A.L. ALS. re. water in Lieut. Oyster's house; Napa Valley Wine Co.'s offer [to buy or supervise?] the Vina harvest, 1893 Aug 19
      - Wilson, M. S. TLS re dentistry bill for Jennie Lathrop, 1904 Aug 4
  - Nash, Herbert C., 1893 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Alexander, Helen ALS re return of her petition, 1893 Aug 17
    - Ashimovitz [?], V. (Russian consulate, S.F.) ALS. re. Imperial Russian horses, Aug 24, 1893
    - Charles, Fannie A. ALS re passing on her condolences to Mrs. Stanford, [1893] June 22
    - Coleman, J.0. ALS. re. rental of a house owned by Mrs. Stanford., Aug 12, 1893
    - Chamberlain, W. H. ALS re claim for services of a Mr. Lombard as stenographer for the League, 1893 Aug 19
    - Foltz, Clara ALS re offer of her services as attorney for Mrs. Stanford; includes her letter to Mrs. Stanford of same date offering her services, 1893 Aug 28
    - Giffard, E. C. ALS re position as French teacher at S.U., 1893 July 27
    - Livingston, G. A. ALS re confusion over his request for RR pass, 1893 Aug 8
    - Lusk, F.C.TLS. re. renting land at Vina., Aug 23, 1893
    - McCarthy, J.B. ALS. re. shipment of 14 letterbooks of Leland Stanford's correspondence to Mrs. Stanford at Menlo Park., Jul 14, 1893
    - McCarthy, J.B. ALS. re. shipment of 5 boxes of letters from Leland Stanford's Washington office, Aug 14, 1893
    - Miller, E. W. ALS. re seeing Mrs. Stanford on her visit to Menlo Park, 1893 Aug 30
    - Raper, A. M. APS would like return of RR passes, 1893 Sep 8
    - Romeike, Henry. TLS. re. Mrs. Stanford's decision to discontinue subscribing to a press-clipping bureau., Aug 16, 1893
    - Southern Pacific Co. TLS. re. box of plans of the Stanford mansion stored in an Oakland S.P. warehouse., Jul 12, 1893
    - Wilson and Wilson TLS re correspondence of James Tanner to Leland Stanford, 1893 Sep 8
  - Cooper, John T. (first recipient of Leland Stanford Jr. Memorial Scholarship)
    - 1900 Feb-Jun (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - H. H. Cooper to J. L. Stanford, Received her letter, religious thoughts, hopes her son John will attend Stanford, 12-Feb-00
      - H. H. Cooper to J. L. Stanford, Trying to enthuse John on upcoming examination, 3-May-00
      - J. L. Stanford to Dr. Jordan, Sending him Cooper letters, 7-May-00
      - H. H. Cooper to J. L. Stanford, John's name not going before State Committee, 26-May-00
      - [Jordan] to J. L. Stanford, Report from John Cooper's principal; letter also has ALS to Charlie [Lathrop?] from J. L. Stanford stating her choice of Cooper as first recipient of Leland Stanford Jr. Scholarship, 30-May-00
      - Jordan to Lathrop, If Cooper not ready, he has list of other possibilities, 4-Jun-00
      - Margaret A. Huston to Mr. Cooper, Reference for John Cooper, undated
      - H. H. Cooper to J. L. Stanford, John working for railroad during the summer, 5-Jun-00
      - H. H. Cooper to J. L. Stanford, Sent her Margaret Huston's letter about John, 5-Jun-00
      - J. L. Stanford to [Charles Lathrop], Sending more Cooper correspondence; show him favoritism on my account, 7-Jun-00
      - J. L. Stanford to Mountford Wilson, Relates history of the funds in the Leland Stanford, Jr. Scholarship; has selected a room in Encina Hall, Jun 9, 1900 copy
      - J. L. Stanford to [Charles Lathrop], Re bonds for scholarship, 9-Jun-00
      - G.A. Clark to J. L. Stanford, Re Cooper letters and progress of selection for scholarship, 11-Jun-00
      - G.A. Clark to J. L. Stanford, Found the letters and sent them to Lathrop, 14-Jun-00
      - H. H. Cooper to Charles Lathrop, His son has good recommendations; hopes delay is only due to Jordan's absence, 20-Jun-00
      - W. H. Housh to Jordan, Reference for Cooper, 20-Jun-00
    - 1900 Sep-Nov (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - H. H. Cooper to Jordan, Hasn't heard about scholarship, 14-Sep-00
      - Jordan to Cooper, Referred the matter to Charles Lathrop, 17-Sep-00
      - Lathrop to Cooper, Needs to know status of John's academic standing, 18-Sep-00
      - Cooper to Lathrop, Repeats what high school principal had communicated to Jordan earlier, 19-Sep-00
      - Jordan to Lathrop, o one has given him exact statement of Cooper's degree to advancement, but is willing to enter him as special exemption, ept 20, 1900
      - Jordan to Lathrop, Boy is not technically ready but competent to carry on university work; will abide by your decision re his admittance, 21-Sep-00
      - [Lathrop?] to Jordan, Wrote to Mr. Cooper to send the boy, 6-Oct-00
      - Lathrop to Geo. Adderson, Cooper is coming and will occupy the Leland Stanford Junior Memorial Room in Encina free of charge, 6-Oct-00
      - H. H. Cooper to Jordan, Thanks for interest in his son, 6-Oct-00
      - H. H. Cooper to Lathrop, Thanks for his help, thank his sister for him, 6-Oct-00
      - Lathrop to H. H. Cooper, Gives details of what scholarship will cover, 8-Oct-00
      - H. H. Cooper to Lathrop, John leaves Los Angeles for San Francisco Saturday, 9-Oct-00
      - Jordan to Lathrop, How are the financial details to be arranged, 16-Oct-00
      - Lathrop to Jordan, Cooper's board arranged; has free room at Encina; can you excuse the registration fee, 17-Oct-00
      - Jordan to Lathrop, Registration fee will be excused, 18-Oct-00
      - Jordan to Lathrop, What amount will be given to Cooper, 30-Oct-00
      - Jordan to Lathrop, Cooper just wants to keep expenses within his income; advises not to give more than the board bill, with room rent and registration fees being waived, 5-Nov-00
  - Correspondence re. remodeling of Palo Alto residence, 1887-1890 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Letters primarily directed to Arthur Brown from Jane Stanford; W.A. Rodman and Chas. Austin for firm of Shipley, Rutan, and Coolidge, Architects; and G. W. Clark and Co. Also includes bills and memoranda.
  - Correspondence regarding RR travel during strike, 1894 July 1 - July 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Telegrams among J. L. Stanford, Herbert Nash, A. N. Towne, J. Agler, and Eugene Debs re. safe passage for Jane Stanford during railroad strike.
  - Incoming
    - Anthony, Susan B., 1894-1898 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - ALS. [With transcription] Women's Rights Books for the Stanford Library, Jan 29, 1894
      - A.N.S. Notes to S.U. and S.U. Library (4), Jan 29, 1894
      - ALS. [With transcription] Trip to Palo Alto., May 20, 1895
      - TLS. Susan B. Anthony to J. L. Stanford - wants to use her name as vice-pres. of campaign com., wants her as patron of Nat'l. Council of Women, celebration of Mrs. Stanton's 80th anniversary, Oct 4, 1895
      - ALS Mrs. Stanton's celebration and ticket to Metropolitan Opera., Oct 7-12, 1895 Program for Conferences of the National Council of Women Atlanta, Georgia Nov 10, 1895
      - ALS [With transcription]. Thanks for sending passes to Mrs. Cooper; needs an hour of her time to "secure the end we all so much desire.", Feb 22, 1896
      - ALS [photocopy] would like to have lunch with her; would she sit on platform with Anthony at Sept. 10 event, Aug 23, 1896
      - ALS To visit Palo Alto, Aug 26, 1896
      - ALS Re: RR passes, Calif. campaign, Aug 27, 1896
      - ALS Re: RR passes, Sep 1, 1896
      - ALS Invitation to Opening Rally, Sep 8, 1896
      - ALS Crocker, Republicans, RR Corp., Sep 9, 1896
      - ALS Begging J. L. Stanford to write Mrs. Hearst re: a contribution, Sep 18, 1896
      - ALS Apologizes for last letter, Sep 21, 1896
      - ALS Calif. Suffragettes et. al. Ida H. Harper, Sep 21 poss Sep 4, 1896
      - ALS Asking for autographs of L.Stanford and J. L. Stanford, Mar 14, 1898
      - TLS circ. ltr. Re: 50th anniversary and new Press Bureau, Apr 23, 1898
      - TLS and brochure on biography. Typescript finished, wants to establish a standing fund., Apr 25, 1898
    - A - Ale, circa 1871-1902 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Abbott, Frances Field, ALS re the Jeffries place in Santa Cruz mountains, 1902 Aug 14
      - Abbott, Nathan, ALS re his promotion of University's law department, 1895 June 5
      - Academy of the Visitation, Sister Mary Baptista Linton, ALS: sending Linton's Historical Charts, hopes to see her in the future, May 19, 1888
      - Adderson, George, ALS re successful conclusion of suit, June 29, 1895, March 4 1896
      - Agassiz, Elizabeth Cady Cary (Mrs. Louis) ALS personal, refers to visit in Sierras, Oct 10 1871?
      - Alden, Mary Weed, ALS (with unfinished letter of Sept. 7) re personal and family affairs, mentions Jane's selling of her jewels and her kindergarten work, Oct 22, 1893 and Sep 30, 1895
      - Alexander, C.B., ALS (death of Mrs. Crocker?), Nov 17, 1889
      - Alexander, Harriett, TLS re Pacific Grove property, 4-Dec-01
    - Alla - An, 1893-1896 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Allabach, Lucy,ALS with congratulations on successful conclusion of suit, Mar 5, 1896?
      - Allen, Mrs. C. F.,ALS with genealogy question, Dec-01
      - Allen, Charles H.,ALS in appreciation of opening day ceremonies, Oct 3, 1891
      - Allen, Charles H.,ALS re sending first letter, Nov 1, 1891
      - Allen, M. C.,ALS re sympathy on recent loss, circa 1893
      - Allyn, Nellie L.,ALS re her son Frank who is attending Stanford University, Jan 16, 1895
      - Anderson, James [H.],ALS re successful conclusion of suit, Mar 2, 1896
      - Anderson, Melville B.,ALS re health of his son, Jan 17, 1893
      - Andrews, Frank W.,ALS re set of books he wants to sell to the University, July 8, 1893
      - [Aukam] Bertha K.,ALS re successful conclusion of suit, [1896]
      - Anonymous: 3 letters
    - Blaine, James and Blaine, Harriet, 1891-1896 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Blaine, James G., ALS (torn) and cvr. re his house, includes wedding invitation on marriage of daughter to Walter Damrosch, Feb 24 1891
      - Blaine, James, G., ALS introduction of Mrs. Margaret Sullivan, 1896 Mar 5
      - Blaine, Harriet S., 2 ALS death of her children, husband taken ill, thanks, undated
    - Blodgett, Benjamin C., 1904 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - ALS enjoyed visit to University and offers his help, 1904 May 30
      - ALS enjoyed visit to University, 1904 June 10
      - ALS (and ts copy) leaves matter of salary in her hands, would like some guidance on duties involved, 1904 June 23
      - ALS re salary as organist in chapel and possible teaching duties, 1904 Aug 8
      - ALS is eager to hear her decision; with clipping re recital by Blodgett, 1904 Sep 3
    - Bowley, Mrs. Flora E., 1891 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - ALS re formation of the Mrs. Leland Stanford Div. No. 105 Grand International Auxiliary to the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, 1891 Sep 8
      - ALS in gratitude for her letter and gift to the auxiliary, 1891 Sep 21
      - LS official letter of thanks for donation, 1891 Sep 24
    - Brown, J. E. (owner/editor of San Francisco Vindicator), 1893 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - TLS, with copy of Brown's earlier letter and clippings from San Francisco Vindicator, re his journalistic service on behalf of Sen. Stanford and request for assistance, 1893 July
      - ALS to Susie Bristol (J. L. Stanford secretary) correcting impression he was stating a legal claim on Sen. Stanford's estate, 1893 Aug 14
      - TLS restating his request, 1893 Sep
    - Ba - Barn, 1882-1902 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Bacon, Eugenia Jones, ALS asking help for her nephew to attend Stanford, Nov 13, 1893
      - Badlam, Alexander, ALS thanks for RR pass, 1895 Feb 15
      - Badlam, Alexander, congratulations re government suit, Oct 14, 1895
      - Badlam, Alexander, to Mr. Lathrop with ALS to J. L. Stanford on Judge Ross's decision, Mar 2, 1896
      - Baker, Eliza S., ALS congratulations on legal case, thankful for her son Shirley's four years at Stanford, July 2, 1895
      - Balentine, Mary P. Nimmo, ALS her marriage, government suit., Mar 4, 1896
      - Bancroft. George J., A.N.S. congratulations re government suit, Mar 4 1896
      - Bancroft, H. H., please give the Governor the enclosed volume, 1882 Sep 16
      - Bank of California, acknowledgement of revocation of C. G. Lathrop to sign checks, 1902 July 29
      - Barnes, Mrs. [L.R.], ALS "Annie Laurie article," sympathy, Feb 18, 1896
      - Barnes, Mary Sheldan, A.N.S. congratulations on legal decision, June 29, 1895
    - Barr - Bi, 1892-1901 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Barreda, Matilda A., ALS thank you note, undated
      - Barriolhet, Louise, ALS personal, 1901 Aug 2
      - Barton, Clara, ALS and ptd. card re leaflets she sent, Mar 28, 1892
      - Baucus, Joseph D., TLS re financial problems of Mrs. Christine M. Lathrop, Aug 23, 1893
      - Beatty, John C., ALS congratulations on government suit, Mar 3 1896
      - Beedy, Louis, ALS re resolutions by Stanford Alumni Club on her relinquishing her University powers, undated
      - Bell, Mr. and Mrs. J.T., ALS congratulations on government suit, Mar 3, 1896
      - Benedict, James H., Tel. Mrs. Moses Hopkins et. al. congrats on Judge Ross's decision, [July 1, 189-]
      - Berner, August, Tel. congratulations on victory, Oct 13, 1895
      - Bernieri, Antoinio, ALS shipping marble sculptures; with J. L. Stanford note to C.G. Lathrop re unpacking, May 5, 1901
      - Bishop, Homer, ALS congratulations from a servant, Mar 2, 1896
    - Bl - Bo, 1890-1904 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Black, Samuel, [to D. S. Jordan] congratulations to Stanford U. and Mrs. Stanford, 1895 Oct 13
      - Black, Samuel, congratulatory letter, 1896 Mar 3
      - Black, Winifred (pseud, Annie Laurie), ALS, Mar, 1896
      - Blair, Ethel Ingalls, ALS adjusting to her new home in Kansas City, Mar 22, 1895
      - Blanchard, Ralph, mail is being forwarded to your ship, 1904 Mar 7
      - Blanchard, W. W., statue of Father Serra finished and ready for inspection, 1891 May 9
      - Blanchard, W. W., re names to be put on statue, 1891 May 31
      - Blandford, Walter, thanks for Stanford publications, 1895 May 28
      - Bleakney, Mrs. F.P., ALS re Howard family news, Feb 19, 1896
      - Bledsoe, Benjamin F., ALS (fragment) congratulations on government suit, [1895 or 96?]
      - Bonner, Robert, Tel. congratulations on government suit, Mar 3, 1896
      - Bonte, J.H.C., ALS wishes success with University, 1890 Nov 17
      - Bonte, J.H.C., ALS re opening day ceremonies, 1891 Oct 2
      - Bonte, J.H.C., ALS L.Stanford's endorsement of higher education has made it a necessity, Oct 22, 1892
      - Booth, Lucius A., Tel. congratulations on government suit, Mar 3, 1896
    - Br - Bu, 1892-1901 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Branner, J.C., ALS his loyalty to University [draft and final copies], 16-Nov-01
      - Breckinridge, Louise D. (Mrs. J.C.), ALS and cvr. illness of Mrs. Harrison, Oct 14, 1892
      - Briggs, Mrs. D.D., ALS expresses sympathy, June 3, 1895
      - Brown, Adam, ALS thanks for RR pass, ny Mar 9
      - Brown, James P., ALS congratulations on government suit decision, Mar 1896
      - Brown, Kate, ALS congratulations and begging, July 3, 1895
      - Brugach [Bey], Emile re collection she is buying from him, 1901 July 5
      - Budd, James H., letter of thanks, 1895 May 29
      - Bull, S. A., ALS reminiscences, 1895 Oct 13
      - Bull, S. A., ALS thanks for her letter, more reminiscences, 1895 Nov 10
      - Bull, W.T., ALS Thanks, undated
      - Burke, Bart, TLS recommends J. B. Peakes to handle board at University, 1893 Aug 12
      - Burnell, Charles, ALS class of 1895 supports her in her trials, 1896 Jan 28
      - Burnett, Frances Hodgson, ALS to Mrs. Lippencott to meet J. L. Stanford, lost her son too, preparing a boy for L.S.J.U., [1893]
      - Burr, Geo. L., ALS letter of support, 1895 Sept 4
      - Bush, C.C., Tel. [congratulations], Mar 1896
      - Bushnell, John Eichelberger, ALS and ptd. card congratulations on suit, dedicating new Lutheran Church in Oakland, requests help to buy an organ, 1896 Mar 2
      - Bushnell, John Eichelberger, ALS sending her a letter from Sen. Perkins, 1896 Mar 3
    - Camerino, M., 1901-1904 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - ALS (to Miss Berner) re inscription for Church, 1901 Dec 4
      - ALS re difficulties with inscription for facade of Church, 1901 Dec 4
      - ALS from Constance Camerino seasonal greetings and family news, 1901 Dec 5
      - ALS (with mss. copy) re sending watercolor drawings by Paoletti for mosaics and gives costs, 1901 Dec 19
      - ALS re mosaics for Church, 1901 Dec 31
      - ALS (to Miss Berner) re inscription, work for Museum, his work for next year, 1902 Jan 9
      - ALS hope the drawings have reached you, 1902 Jan 11
      - ALS Paoletti working on drawings for Museum, hopes other drawings reached her, 1902 Feb 11
      - ALS has shipped 6 cases, cannot find view of Abyssinia, suggests ruins of Athens or picture representing Literature, 1902 Mar 26
      - ALS description of two designs by Paoletti, size and cost, 1902 Apr 1
      - ALS he is working for her alone, 1902 Apr 9
      - ALS (and ts copy) received her telegram, needs decision on third picture for Museum, 1902 Apr 14
      - ALS (and ts copy) suggests blue stars to go with gold mosaics in the cupola of the Museum, 1902 Apr 15
      - ALS re Mr. Zampatto and other workers at Stanford, 1902 Aug 14